Madalina Mutihac

Rosenborg gate 34B +47 9188 7333
7014 Trondheim madi.mutihac@gmail.com

Norway http://no.linkedin.com/in/madalinamutihac/

Background and Goals

speed and stability.

I am a software developer with an increasing interest in creating aesthetically compelling user experiences that meet business objectives. My work experience as a developer taught me that responsive, intuitive products are an essential element in everyone's life. Therefore user experience has become my focus for a few years now.

I enjoy experimenting with new technologies, keeping an eye on current trends and I find it rewarding to deliver meaningful products.

Experience

Betradar (Sportradar) | Trondheim, Norway (4 years)

Software Developer with Product Responsibility | 2012 – Present Software Developer - April 2010 | 2012

- Leading a growing remote development team in designing, developing and maintaining a set of front-end applications written in ActionScript 3 and Flex.
- Partly working on server side code (Java), with which the front-end applications connect to, as well as on a series of web interfaces (PHP, Javascript). Focus on
- In charge of improving user experience for outside customers. A web application (written in ActionScript) for monitoring live and historical sports matches. Focus
 on speed, organizing large amounts of data in an easy and accessible manner. Involves continuous communication with product owners and the design teams in
 order to improve the usability and visibility of the product.
- In charge of creating and maintaing an Adobe AIR application for covering live sporting events. Users need visualization of real-time data, continuous feedback on actions, and to easily find next logical steps under stressful, time-sensitive conditions. Because the application is mission critical, stability is crucial.
- Working closely with product owners, the design team and my development team to create wireframes and visual mockups.
- Contributing to product roadmap discussions.

DataPro AS | Ålesund, Norway (3 months)

Java Developer | January 2010 – April 2010

- As part of a small team, I worked on re-implementing a legacy logistics system into an optimized J2EE application. I had the opportunity to make design and implementation decisions, which would lead to an improved workflow for inventory management.
- This position gave me insight into how warehouse software is organized, but most of all helped me work on my people skills, as re-writing a legacy system meant a lot of interaction and communication with developers of the legacy product.

COMODO | Iasi, Romania (6 months)

Software Developer | March 2009 - August 2009

- I was part of the design and development of the Live PC support desktop client, a computer maintenance suite.
- My main work was on the Swing-based module used in production by our technical support engineers. I also wrote parts of the web administration interface (Java and Wicket).

SC AdWork Film S.R.L | Bucharest, Romania (2 years)

Web developer | 2006–2008

- Designed, developed and maintained the website of Autoforumtv, an automobile TV show.
- Managed site structure, news data and media (photo galleries, video features) and decided on how to present it in a relevant way.
- Provided technical support for usability issues and critical site problems, as a consultant.

Other relevant work

Research of Java Web Services Frameworks, in collaboration with SYNYGY Inc. | 2008–2009

- As part of my thesis work, I analyzed the 3 most used Java web services frameworks at the time: Apache Axis 2, Apache CXF and Glassfish Metro. The end result of the comparison was describing the differences and demonstrating them by using a set of enterprise tools that Synygy relied on daily.
- This was the first time that I worked in a big company, which helped me understand enterprise work culture and good code practices. Apart from the academic research, I have learned new tools, such as Spring, Hibernate, JSF, PostgreSQL, Metro and Apache CXF.

Web developer | 2005–2006

• While studying computer science in high school and university, I have been involved in different freelancing projects, mainly in web programming. I have worked with web technologies (CSS, HTML, PHP, MySQL, XML, JavaScript, JSF, etc) on projects mainly for non-profit organizations, such as: the Computer Science Student Association of Iasi and the Iasi County Chess Association.

Education

2005 - 2008 - "Al. I. Cuza" Computer Science Faculty of Iasi, Romania

Bachelor in Computer Science, Thesis: "Capabilities analysis of Java Web Services Frameworks", in collaboration with Synygy Inc.

2001 - 2005 - "Gr. Moisil" Computer Science Highschool, Iasi, Romania

Technical skills

I have been writing code, improving usability and experimenting with new software since 2005.

Most recently, the majority of code I have written has been in Actionscript (styling in CSS) and Java (communication with server through XML), but I have experience in PHP and Javascript (JQuery). I have started my programming experience by studying C and C++ in high school and university, and I have tried out a variety of other languages and frameworks, like Python (and Django), web frameworks (Wicket, Play, JSF), Javascript frameworks (DOJO).

I am used to working within a Scrum/Agile environment and enthusiastic about it. I have used SVN and GIT for versioning systems, and my OS proficiency extends to Windows, Mac OSX and Linux (mainly Ubuntu).

Language skills

- Romanian: native;English: fluent; TO
- English: fluent; TOEFL IBT score 111/120, 1st prize awarded at the county competition in English and participation to the National English Competition, 2004
 Norwegian: average; Norwegian Language and Civilization for Foreign Students, 2009 2010, Høgskulen i Volda, Norwegian Language course, levels 9–10,
- Spring 2010, Folkeuniversitetet Midt-Norge, Trondheim

Strong points

- Good communication skills: I like making the work environment friendly and positive, while keeping ideas flowing and problems discussed.
 Service-minded: I believe in good communication with customers and product owners.
- Proactive: I tend to think in perspective, to work passionately and to invest in my own professional development.
 Dedicated and hard working: I am quality conscious

References available upon request.